# Alpesh Gevariya

https://www.designwithalpesh.com

alpesh.gevariya.15@gmail.com



## **ABOUT ME**

A designer, with 8+ years of professional experience in UX/UI design, worked in a wide range of environments from start-ups and IT consultancies. I am passionate about bringing inclusivity into design solutions by bridging physical and digital worlds to help businesses to identify the changing needs of users.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER UX/UI, ESCALE SOLUTIONS

India (Jan 2021 - Present)

- Synced with product owner to identify user profiles, conducted user research and set-up ideation workshops with design team and implemented **5+ product features**.
- Contributed to the **Design System**, designed components for consistency throughout product.
- Designed user interfaces and experiences for a wide range of clients across industries, including healthcare, e-commerce, and education.
- Conducted user research with over 100 participants and designed a new website, resulting in a 16% increase in revenue.

#### HEAD OF UX/UI DESIGN DEPARTMENT, CORUSCATE SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD. India (Jul 2019 - Apr 2021)

- Led a team of **8+ creative people** for **4 years** and was responsible for task management, regular meetings, task allocation, interviews, appraisals, managing deliverables, and decision making
- Collaborated with the product development team to design and implement highly interactive, dataintensive web applications and created 250+ mobile app UI designs.
- Illustrated design ideas using sitemaps, storyboards, and process flows.
- Conducted interviews with 100+ end users and designed a new website and its revenue growth by 16%.
- Received 95% positive feedback on 17 completed projects.

## **UX/UI DESIGNER**, CORUSCATE SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD.

India (May 2013 - Apr 2016)

- Responsible for 1.2 million+ monthly visitors to give the best user experience with my expertise.
- Invented 50+ marketing collateral and improved engagement ratio by 20%.
- Worked with developers and product managers to develop 9+ new products that brought in a 137%
- Conducted user research with over 100 participants and designed a new website, resulting in a 16% increase in revenue.

## **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Computer Applications (B.C.A.)

(2016 - 2019)

Veer Narmad South Gujarat University, India

#### **UX/UI CERTIFICATION - 9 months**

(2012-2013)

Red & White Multimedia Education, India

## **CERTIFICATION**

**Figma** (2023)

WeLoveNoCode

AdobeXD (2023)

Uxcel

UX/UI Design (2023)

WeLoveNoCode

UX concepts validation (2023)

intouxdesign

## **SKILLS**

Design Thinking Tools, Quantitative and Qualitative Research, Problem Definition and Hypothesis Creation, Personas, Stakeholder Mapping, Information Architecture, Wire-framing, Prototyping and Usability Testing Methods, Heuristic Analysis, UX Writing, Storytelling and Power Point Presentations, Service Design Blueprint, Business Model Canvas, UI Design, Visual Design and Facilitating and designing Workshops.

## **TOOLS**

Figma, AdobeXD, Sketch, Zeplin, Jira, Confluence, Notion, Miro, Mural, Webflow, Wix, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, MS Office, Google Suite, Power Point, Key Note, Wordpress

## LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

English: Native

German: Elementary, A1 (learning A2)

Hindi: Native